# PHAN XUAN THIEN

#### 1. PERSONAL DETAILS

Full name: Phan Xuan Thien.

Date of birth: March 03,1987.

Gender: Male.

Nationality: Vietnamese.

Hometown: Hue City, Vietnam.

Mobile Phone: (+81) 80 95773387; (+84) 933993387

Email: xuanthiencs@gmail.com; thien@nii.ac.jp

Skype: xuanthien.phan; LinkedIn: Xuan-Thien Phan.

Address: 6/13 Han Mac Tu Street, Vi Da Ward, Hue City, Vietnam.



# 2. PERSONAL PROFILE

A motivated and responsible IT worker seeking for a suitable job in the area of information science and technology. I hold Bachelor degree, and Master degree (with very good grade, ranked at top 5% of the course) in Computer Science and Engineering, conferred by Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (Đại Học Bách Khoa TP. HCM). I have excellent skills in English, with over 4 years working oversea (Switzerland and Japan) via various engineering/researching activities and projects, and various conducted scientific publications. I'm hardworking, eager to learn, have genuine interest in engineering and scientific works in information technology. I have strong interest in learning about financial investment and worldwide financial markets. I also have strong skills in communication, professional presentation, connecting people/colleagues in the working field. I have experience in organizing various academic seminars and activities for the Vietnamese Research Community (NII-Vietnamese) in National Institute of Informatics (NII – Tokyo, Japan) over the past 3 years.

### 3. EDUCATION

- From 2002 2005: study Gifted High School Program at Hue University of Science (class of Mathematics), Hue city, Vietnam. Graduate grade: Very good.
- From 2005 2010: study Bachelor of Engineering at the Faculty of Computer Science & Engineering, Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (Đại Học Bách

- Khoa TP. HCM), Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam. Graduate grade: **Good**. Average score: 7.52/10.
- From September 2010 April 2013: study Master of Computer Science at the Faculty of Computer Science & Engineering, Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (Đại Học Bách Khoa TP. HCM), Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam. Graduate grade: **Very good**. Average score: **8.24/10** (**Rank 5%**).

#### 4. ACADEMIC DEGREE & CERTIFICATE

- Bachelor of Engineering Computer Science & Engineering, conferred by Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (Đại Học Bách Khoa TP. HCM), 2010.
- Master of Engineering Computer Science, conferred by Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology (Đại Học Bách Khoa TP. HCM), April 2013. Grade: Very good (ranked at top 5% in the course).
- English certificate: IELTS 5.5 (taken in November 2011).
- Certificate of Completion Research Internship Program, conferred by the University of Applied Sciences of Western Switzerland, Fribourg, Switzerland, 2012.
- Certificate of Completion Research Internship Program, conferred by the National Institute of Informatics (NII), Tokyo, Japan, 2013.

### 5. COMPUTER & RESEARCH SKILLS

- Can program well with Java and C/C++ (having experiences in these programming language by frequently use through some past projects), SQL, HTML, Prolog, Lisp, SmallTalk and Assembly.
- Have knowledge with technologies: Maven, Spring Framework, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Drop Wizards, RESTful Web Service, Ext JS, JUnit.
- Have strong knowledge and skill in Object Oriented Programming design and UML.
- Database systems: can work with database management systems like MySQL and Oracle.
- Tools: can work proficiently with Eclipse IDE (over 4 year experiences), Netbean for programming, and Virtual Paradigm for UML 10.0 for modeling software and systems.
- Operating Systems: can work well with Mac OSX (over 5 years working on Mac OSX), Window, Unix/Linux (over 4 years, used frequently for real researching experiments).

- Other technical skills: had experience in building a plug-in for Eclipse IDE.
- Research skills: good at mathematics, problem analyzing and solving, logical inference. I have over 4 years experience in doing research in Computer Science (Computer Networks, Software-Defined Network [SDN], Ad-Hoc Networks, Network Traffic Monitoring and Analysis).

### 6. SOFT SKILLS

• Excellent skills in English.

Very good at reading English technical documents, academic documents in computer science and engineering, excellent at report writing and extremely self-confident in English communication and presentation.

I have been living and working oversea for over 4 years, in which English is the main language used for works and daily life. I have been communicating frequently with partners, colleagues/researchers in English. I wrote various professional documents in English including my scientific publications, technical/scientific reports. I have conducted various presentations in international conferences and meetings using English. Overall, English is also my hobby, which I have been using and practicing everyday.

- Basic skills in Japanese language.
- Good at communication skill, presentation skill, problems analyzing and solving, group working skill.
- Have experience in organizing professional/academic events and seminars.

#### 7. WORK EXPERIENCE

- From June 2009 August 2009: work in the Internship Program in FPT Software Company Limited, Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam.
- August 2010 December 2010: Work in the project "Building a tool for supporting POP-C++ object file management and execution". This project was also conducted for my Bachelor thesis at the Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology, Vietnam.

Project detail: Developing a plug-in for Eclipse that supports users manage POP-C++ object files which are placed distributively among computers in a Grid environment. This tool supports processing management tasks such as migrating, tracking, executing POP-C++ object files,... in the grid environment. This plug-in was developed based on Java technology. This project supports the research in the field of Grid Computing led by Prof. Nam Thoai (Dean of the faculty of Computer Science

- and Engineering) and Prof. Tran Van Hoai at Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology, Vietnam.
- From September 2011 February 2012: Do a research project in the Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering, Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology, Vietnam. Research field: Software-Defined Network and OpenFlow. I have conducted an international publication in this project.
- From February 2012 August 2012: Research Internship, Prof. Pierre Kuonen Laboratory, University of Applied Science of Western Switzerland (in Fribourg, Switzerland). Research field: Computer Networks (Software-Defined Networks and OpenFlow).
- From April 2013 to August 2013: work as a Java Software Engineer in KMS-Technology Co. Ltd., Vietnam.
  - Project Detail: Building the HMS System for managing Expense Data of medical employees (doctors, nurses, ...) and services for a customer in USA. Using Technologies: Maven, Oracle Database, Spring framework, Spring Data JPA, Hibernate, Drop Wizards, RESTful Web Service, Ext JS.
- From September 2013 March 2014: Research Internship at the National Institute of Informatics (NII), Tokyo, Japan. Do research in the area of Computer Networks (focus on Wireless Networks and Access Networks). Research Topic: Access network for disaster recovery (an emerging research topic in NII and Japan).
- April 2014 April 2015: Lecturer at the University of Information Technology, Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.
- From October 2014 now: Research Assistant at Prof. Fukuda Laboratory, National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan. Research field: Network traffic monitoring and analysis, Software-Defined Network (SDN). Project: Research for a solution for finegrained and distributed framework for traffic monitoring and analysis in Software-Defined Network.

# 8. PUBLICATION

- Xuan Thien Phan, and Kensuke Fukuda, "SDN-Mon: Fine-grained traffic monitoring framework in Software-Defined Networks", *Journal of Information Processing (JIP)*, Information Processing Society of Japan, vol. 25, pp.182–190, 2017.
- Xuan Thien Phan, and Kensuke Fukuda. Toward a flexible and scalable monitoring framework in Software-Defined Networks. In *Network Monitoring and Management Workshops, IEEE International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications (AINA), 2017*, pp. 403–408, Taipei, Taiwan, March 2017.

- Xuan Thien Phan, Quang Tran Minh, Kien Nguyen, Toan Nguyen, Hoang Tran Viet, and Shigeki Yamada, "A devices-association mechanism for Wi-Fi Direct based Internet connection establishment", IEICE Technical Committee on Mobile Network and Applications (MoNA), Jan. 24, 2014, Matsuyama, Japan, Jan. 2014.
- Xuan Thien Phan, Quang Tran Minh, Kien Nguyen, Nam Thoai, Shigeki Yamada GICS: Group-based Internet Connection Spreading Architecture for Disaster Recovery, Proc. of IEEE 29th International Conference on Information Networking and Applications Workshops (WAINA), 2015, Gwangju, Korea 478-483 Mar 2015.
- Xuan Thien Phan, Nam Thoai, Pierre Kuonen, "A collaborative model for routing in multi-domains OpenFlow networks". In *IEEE International Conference on Computing, Management and Telecommunications*, pages 278-283, Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam, January 2013.

### 9. SOCIAL ACTIVITY

• From June 28, 2006 – July 28, 2006: participate in Green Summer volunteer campaign – the annual volunteer campaign organized by Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology. My team was assigned to build a small bridge (about 20 meters long) and renovate some roads in a small village in Tra Vinh province, Vietnam. We worked and lived with the local inhabitant for about one month. The campaign was concluded when we completed building the new bridge and renovating the roads, and handed them to the local inhabitant. We received a Certificate of Merit from the committee of Youth Union of my university for completing the assigned works well.

#### 10. INTEREST

- Travel, football, swimming, listening to BBC radio, watching BBC/CNN news.
- Joining group activities and social activities.